Ken Eucker

Portland, Oregon, United States



keneucker@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/keneucker

Summary

I am a full stack developer, classically trained in object oriented programming, who likes to write universal javascript, with extensive experience building the backend of web connected properties. I have a diverse set of skills writing in the serverside languages C#, PHP, Javascript, and the clientside languages HTML, Javascript, CSS, JSX, including the database languages mysql, MSSQL, and Mongodb.

The latter half of my career has been focused on building WordPress applications and working with popular plugins and themes. I have developed and launched WordPress 5.0 applications on WordPress VIP over the last two years.

Experience



Senior Node Developer

Clevertech

Oct 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

100% Remote Engineer on a 100% Remote Team. I attend daily stand-ups with clients in New York, USA. I am available to clients for a six hour work stretch each day of the workweek and outside of that I choose what hours I work. I participate in sprint planning and estimating each week and do client demos each Friday of the week. I maintain a healthy work-life balance that would not be as successful if it wasn't for the dedication of Clevertech to the well-being of the team and team members.

I worked on the Sam Harris website running on WordPress VIP and was brought onto the team to transition them away from WooCommerce to using Piano.IO and other platforms to manage subscriptions and analytics.

⅓ Contract Software Engineer

Ken Eucker LLC

Jan 2019 - Present (1 year 11 months +)

"All dogs are therapy dogs, some are just freelancing."

Principal engineer seeking contract, contract-to-hire, remote, or on-premises computer software services ranging from web development to app development and more. I work with local small businesses in various markets. I also participate in the gig economy on UpWork taking on remote, short term, contracts while travelling the Pacific Northwest.

Co-Founder

BikeTagOrg

Apr 2018 - Present (2 years 8 months +)

Co-Founder of the BikeTagOrg organization and Lead Architect for the website and web application.

Developed the app from scratch in Node.JS as the sole software engineer and developer on the project.

Running weekly meetings for checking in with BikeTag Ambassadors from all over the world.

As Co-Founder with my longtime friend Evan, we have started a project to compile and track all information about the game of BikeTag both in the past, how it moved from a photo tag game to a motorcycle-based photo tag game all over the world to now a regional/city-based photo tag game played by local communities. BikeTag.Org provides a way for anyone to play the game of BikeTag in a given region and recently launched in cities all over the world including; Indianapolis, Indiana Seattle, Washington Vienna, Austria Vancouver, BC and more!



Full Stack Developer

Uncorked Studios

Apr 2019 - Jun 2019 (3 months)

Full stack development on a WordPress 5.0 website to be deployed on the WordPress VIP platform and follows the coding standards outlined for WordPress VIP. Custom theme and plugin development with the new, React based, Gutenberg editor and integrated NodeJS build tools for compiling scripts for both the admin backend and the client frontend. The website featured stories and statistics about a company's diversity programs and included components built in React and d3.



Web Developer

Digital Trends

Feb 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Full Stack Web Developer working in PHP, Node, HTML, and Javascript on a Wordpress platform that serves content to over 5,000 concurrent users a day. In my primary role as a shared resource for another department in the organization, I develop solutions and maintain integrations for all of the needs of that department including automating processes. Daily participant in standup meetings, software project planning meetings, and system architecture meetings. As a self starting leader on a team of leaders, I interface with stakeholders and other team members to continuously iterate on solutions that have a direct impact on our digital publication businesses.

During my time at Digital Trends I developed a new ESP integration from the ground up using testdriven development methodologies, refactored newsletter emails and the code that runs the signup modules on the site, implemented a couple of linking features on our articles, and implemented a new article type with a slideshow; all for the WordPress platform of digitaltrends.com.

My greatest work at Digital Trends is an end to end solution for encapsulating our adcode with site-specific integration code and business logic which is deployed to AWS S3, Lambda, and Api Gateway. A project that started as a skunkworks solution for my own process which I whole heartedly developed into a fully featured build automation tool.

I also upped my foosball game.



Freelance Software Engineer

Seven Twenty Studios LLC Jun 2011 - Jan 2017 (5 years 8 months) Custom software development and systems architecture engineer for web connected technologies in both the business and personal sectors. I collaborate on small teams with diversely separate sets of skills to deliver websites. Project technologies include a focus on PHP, HTML, and MySql with equal experience in C# and ASP.NET and MSSQL. I enjoy projects that enable efficient client facing changes as well as automating underlying architecture decisions.

In 2014 I began contracting full time as a remote employee. I continue to work on small teams as a collaborative developer as well as consulting with interactive producers to provide long term architectural designs that benefit the business needs that clients are looking for. I enjoy developing code using github as an all-encompassing development solution and delivering solutions from design to version 2 iterations and anywhere in between.

Web Developer

Solid Digital

Mar 2016 - Dec 2016 (10 months)

Participated in client meetings, standups, development planning sessions, and company wide tactic meetings as a web developer.

I was an active polyglot at Solid and I include myself on projects for the web using the Microsoft stack, PHP and Mysql stack, as well as pure HTML and Javascript website projects. I interface with project managers and clients to provide new features and implementations to existing sites as well as maintenance and issues that arise.

Participated with other developers on the team in sprint planning, story and defect weighting, and tech roundtables about new and exciting technologies.

Contract Web Developer

R\West

Mar 2014 - Apr 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Backend web services developer and software architecture designer focusing on projects in php, mysql, javascript, and html. Developed concurrently on version one and version two implementations that saw growth and reached scalability. Agile methodologies and version control using github while working directly with server environments for deployment.

V Software Development Engineer

Viewpoint

Dec 2011 - Jan 2014 (2 years 2 months)

Developer role in scrum process on systems team: attended daily scrums, participated in weighting sprints, defect ticket management.

Coordinated development efforts with Project Manager, Support, and Quality Assurance teams.

Core development in ASP.NET C#, Multi-Tier SQL, VB.NET Winforms on flagship Viewpoint Construction Software.

Software Developer I

Overland Agency

May 2010 - Jul 2011 (1 year 3 months)

Team developer and scrum participant. Worked mostly in bug fixing, qa testing, and technical design contributor of a proprietary CMS offering customizations for various clients. Worked within ASP.NET and MSSQL for both client and server side enhancements to existing projects.

Lead Silverlight development for all projects: "Fresh Local Music" Delivered a Silverlight out of browser music app that runs on laptops in the store locations and updates external database.

Education



Oregon Institute of Technology

Bachelors of Science, Software Engineering Technology 2006-2010 2006 - 2010

Skills

C# • ASP.NET • jQuery • .NET • PHP • Visual Studio • Software Development • HTML 5 • Web Development • Microsoft SQL Server